<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Amanda C. Perofsky, PhD</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Amanda C. Perofsky, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Human Mobility and Respiratory Virus Transmission</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/mobility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/mobility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the COVID-19 pandemic, mobile phone location data became crucial for tracking population movements and evaluating control strategies for SARS-CoV-2. I began working with cellphone mobility data in 2020, first to forecast COVID-19 outbreaks on military bases for U.S. DoD, and later to analyze relationships between population mobility and &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciac055&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;healthcare-seeking behavior in South Africa&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48528-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;respiratory virus transmission in Seattle&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mobility-behavior-and-respiratory-virus-transmission-dynamics-in-the-seattle-metropolitan-area&#34;&gt;Mobility behavior and respiratory virus transmission dynamics in the Seattle metropolitan area&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Collaborators: &lt;a href=&#34;https://seattleflu.org/about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Seattle Flu Study investigators&lt;/a&gt;  from University of Washington, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle Children&amp;rsquo;s Research Institute, National Institutes of Health, and Institute for Disease Modeling&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infectious Disease Forecasting and Scenario Modeling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/forecasting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;operational-involvement-in-the-covid-19-pandemic-response-and-disease-predictions&#34;&gt;Operational involvement in the COVID-19 pandemic response and disease predictions&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2022 – present, Contributor to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/flu/weekly/flusight/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;US CDC FluSight Forecasting Collaboration&lt;/a&gt; . Submitted weekly short-term forecasts of influenza hospitalizations during the 2022-23, 2023-24, 2024-25, and 2025-26 seasons.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2022 – present, Contributor to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://fluscenariomodelinghub.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;US Influenza Scenario Modeling Hub&lt;/a&gt; . Submitted long-term scenario projections of influenza hospitalizations during the 2022-23, 2023-24, 2024-25, and 2025-26 seasons.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2023 – 2025, &lt;a href=&#34;https://seattleflu.org/sars-cov-2-forecasts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dashboard of SARS-CoV-2 variant forecasts for Washington and other US states&lt;/a&gt; , hosted by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://seattleflu.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Seattle Flu Study&lt;/a&gt;  (In collaboration with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nextstrain.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nextstrain&lt;/a&gt;  team)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2020 – 2022, Developed the analysis and provided technical support to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nicd.ac.za/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;South Africa&amp;rsquo;s National Institute for Communicable Diseases&lt;/a&gt;  for their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nicd.ac.za/diseases-a-z-index/disease-index-covid-19/surveillance-reports/private-consultations-excess-respiratory-encounters/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;COVID-19 Private Consultations Excess Respiratory Encounters Reports&lt;/a&gt; . Reports tracked excess respiratory encounters at hospitals, emergency departments, and primary care providers across different age groups and provinces. Reports were updated from September 2020 to April 2022.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2019 – 2022, Contributor to the US Department of Defense COVID + ILI Forecasting Collaboration. Submitted weekly short-term forecasts of influenza-like illness and COVID-like illness cases on US military bases during the 2019-20, 2020-21, and 2021-22 seasons.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influenza Evolution and Ecology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/influenza/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/influenza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-effects-of-antigenic-drift-and-subtype-interference-on-annual-influenza-epidemics-in-the-united-states&#34;&gt;The effects of antigenic drift and subtype interference on annual influenza epidemics in the United States&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Collaborators: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fic.nih.gov/About/Staff/epidemiology-population-studies/Pages/default.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cécile Viboud (NIH)&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;https://bedford.io/team/john-huddleston/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;John Huddleston (Fred Hutch)&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;https://bedford.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Trevor Bedford (Fred Hutch)&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.icahn.mssm.edu/krammerlab/dr-krammer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Florian Krammer (Mt. Sinai)&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.who.int/initiatives/global-influenza-surveillance-and-response-system&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;WHO Global Influenza Surveillance and Response System (GISRS) Collaborating Centers in Atlanta, London, Melbourne, and Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Influenza viruses continually accumulate genetic changes in epitopes of two major surface proteins, hemagglutinin (HA) and neuraminidase (NA), in a process called &amp;ldquo;antigenic drift.&amp;rdquo; Antigenic drift enables flu viruses to evade immune recognition, leaving previously exposed individuals susceptible to reinfection and requiring regular updates to the flu vaccine. Antigenic drift is expected to increase host susceptibility, leading to more flu cases and in turn earlier, larger, or more severe epidemics. However, epidemiological evidence for the impact of antigenic evolution on seasonal flu outbreaks is conflicting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhD: Gut Microbiomes in Wild Mammals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecological-evolutionary-and-behavioral-determinants-of-gut-microbiomes-in-malagasy-mammals&#34;&gt;Ecological, evolutionary, and behavioral determinants of gut microbiomes in Malagasy mammals&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Advisor: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio.utexas.edu/research/meyers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lauren Ancel Meyers (UT-Austin)&lt;/a&gt; ; Collaborators: &lt;a href=&#34;https://liberalarts.utexas.edu/anthropology/faculty/rl2273&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Rebecca Lewis (UT-Austin)&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;https://liberalarts.utexas.edu/anthropology/faculty/ad26693&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Anthony Di Fiore (UT-Austin)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mammalian gut microbial communities govern host development, metabolism, immune function, and physiology, through interactions that range from commensal or mutualistic to pathogenic. However, the relative contributions of vertical, horizontal, and environmental transmission to gut microbiome composition are not well understood. For my dissertation research, I integrated field-collected data, molecular analyses, and computational and statistical modeling to study how social networks and proximity to other host species influence the gut microbial communities of wild mammals inhabiting Kirindy Mitea National Park in western Madagascar. This research was conducted as part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.la.utexas.edu/ankoatsifaka/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Sifaka Research Project&lt;/a&gt; , a long-term research study led by &lt;a href=&#34;https://liberalarts.utexas.edu/anthropology/faculty/rl2273&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Rebecca Lewis (UT-Austin)&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
